<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<places>
	
	<place>
		<title>1. Immaculate Conception Cathedral</title>
		<image>images/boac.jpg</image>
		<content>Boac Cathedral is one of the historical tourist spots in Marinduque. It dates back to the Spanish colonizers who initiated the construction of the Cathedral. It’s known for its Gothic inspired architecture with resemblance to the churches in Latin America.
			During the revolution against the Spaniards, Filipino warriors would often come here to seek blessing before heading out for war. The church also saw the blessing of the Philippine Revolutionary Flag in 1899.
		</content>
		<location> Mataas na Bayan 4900 Boac Marinduque </location>
	</place>
	
	<place>
		<title>2. Amoingon Beach</title>
		<image>images/amoingon.jpg</image>
		<content>If you like gazing at corals and colorful schools of fish rather than swimming and grilling, then you shouldn’t miss Amoingon Beach in Marinduque. Its waters are so teeming with marine life that many would call it the snorkeling capital of Marinduque. Still, if you’re not a fan of marine life or anything like that, you can still have fun above the clear shallow waters of Amoingon Beach. Get some fresh air and sunshine outdoors, or rent the nearest transient house and inhale the smell of the sea every morning while jogging. 
		</content>
		<location> Amoingon, Boac 4900 Marinduque </location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>3. Kabugsakan Falls</title>
		<image>images/kabugsakan.jpg</image>
		<content>
			This falls is ideal for picnics and nature based activities, it is a popular spot among the locals being proximate to the poblacion of Boac, the capital town.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Tugas, Boac, Marinduque</location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>4. Duyay Cave</title>
		<image>images/.jpg</image>
		<content>Explore the Duyay Cave, which is located in Duyay, Boac, Marinduque, Philippines. The caves are regarded to be even more enthralling than Bathala Caves. The interior is very huge and dark, filled with stalactite formations. Only few visitors have explored the entire length of caves and tunnels, which are estimated to end in Tapuyan, Gasan.
		</content>
		<location>  Duyay, Boac, Marinduque </location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>5. Mount Baliis</title>
		<image>images/baliis.jpg</image>
		<content>Watch the cloud and see the beauty of sunset and sunrise in Mount Baliis. This place is known to offer a view of a sea of clouds.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Bantay in the town of Boac</location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>6. Marinduque Wildlife Sanctuary</title>
		<image>images/wildfire.webp</image>
		<content>A Haven for Endangered Species in the Philippines. The sanctuary is home to a variety of flora and fauna, including rare and endangered species, making it a haven for nature lovers and conservationists. One of the highlights of the sanctuary is the Philippine tarsier, which is one of the smallest primates in the world and is considered a vulnerable species due to habitat loss and poaching. Aside from the tarsiers, the sanctuary also houses a variety of bird species, such as the Philippine eagle, the Palawan peacock-pheasant, and the Mindoro bleeding-heart dove. The area is also home to various plant species, including the Narra tree and the Rattan palm.
		Visiting the Marinduque Wildlife Sanctuary offers a unique opportunity to observe these animals and plants in their natural habitats while supporting their conservation efforts. The sanctuary is also an excellent place for outdoor activities such as birdwatching, trekking, and nature photography.
		Marinduque Wildlife Sanctuary includes almost 9,000 hectares of Central Marinduque timberland. This woodland area is home to a broad range of flora and wildlife, including imperiled Rufous Hornbill (Rufous hydrocorax), giant cloud pig (Phloeomys pallidus), and indigenous butterfly, reptile, insect and bird species. 
		This vast space is one the few areas in the Philippines that have been designated as a Wildlife Sanctuary in light of the abundance of flora and fauna that can be found here. To get here, you'll have to go on a trek that can last about 2 hours, depending on your pace. As you make you way along the trail, you'll see rolling hills, breathtaking views, and even small waterfalls in certain areas. 
		</content>
		<location>Tumagabok, Boac, Marinduque</location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>7. Marinduque Provincial Capitol</title>
		<image>images/capitol.jpg</image>
		<content>An Island Luxury Resort
			All 20 hectares of Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa are mountainous terrain, with its highest point at 114 meters above sea-level. To seasoned travelers, images of the picturesque island of Santorini in Greece will come into mind upon reaching the resort. Common to both are its rolling terrains and immaculate white buildings perched atop its cliffs: white structures that reflect the sun and contrast with the azure blue seas below.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Santol, Boac Marinduque</location>
	</place>
	<place>
		<title>8. Hinulugan Falls</title>
		<image>images/hinulugan.jpg</image>
		<content>These waterfalls are visited by many tourists all year round. There is a cave where water also enters. Aside from the Hinulugan, there are also two more falls in the area, namely the Magdumog-Dumog Falls and Batingaw Falls in Tumagabok, which is commonly known as “Busay”, which is the local term for “waterfalls”. This means other waterfalls elsewhere in the province are also called by that name.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Sabong, Boac Marinduque  </location>
	</place>

	<!-- BUENAVISTA -->
	<buenavista>
		<title>1. Mount Malindig</title>
		<image>images/malindig.jpg</image>
		<content>A challenging trek to the island’s highest peak for adventure seekers. Dominating the skyline south of Marinduque is Mt. Malindig, an inactive volcano. Dense forest covers its upper half. Found in abundance are giant trees, moss forest and wild orchids. The rest is nearly deforested due to the slash and burn method of farming. This however, does not diminish the attraction of Mt. Malindig, which until now remains an excellent place for mountain climbing, camping and bird watching. According to local folklore, the mountain is believed to have been inhabited by a powerful diwata (a supernatural being) named Diwata Malindig. It is said that Diwata Malindig was a protector of the people and the mountain, and that she would manifest as a beautiful woman in order to guide and warn those who dared to climb the peak. Aside from its mythical roots, Mount Malindig has also played an important role in the history of Marinduque. During the Spanish colonial era, the mountain served as a refuge for locals who were fleeing from Spanish soldiers. Today, Mount Malindig continues to be a popular destination for hikers and adventurers. The climb to the summit can take up to 8 hours.
		</content>
		<location> Brgy. Sihi, Buenavista Marinduque </location>
	</buenavista>
	<buenavista>
		<title>2. Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa</title>
		<image>images/bellaroca.jpg</image>
		<content>Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa in Marinduque is distinct from the other upscale, luxury resorts of its category anywhere in the country. All 20 hectares of Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa is mountainous terrain, with its highest point at 114 meters above sea-level. To many seasoned travellers, the images of the picturesque island of Santorini in Greece come to mind upon approaching the resort. Common to both are its rolling terrain and immaculate white buildings perched atop its cliffs: white structures that reflect the sun and contrast with the azure blue sea below. Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa is located on a small mountain island of the southern coast of Marinduque and offers 69 luxurious deluxe suites, casas, terrazas and private villas (with individual Jacuzzis and infinity pools). Guests relax in utmost privacy while enjoying the resort's complete aqua sports facilities, a full spa and wellness facility, a 9-hole golf course and other land-based recreational activities. Guests arrive on the island direct via commercial flights (SEAIR or Zest Air), private helicopters, chartered flights from Manila to Marinduque or onboard an exclusive luxury yacht.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Lipata, Buenavista Marinduque </location>
	</buenavista>
	<buenavista>
		<title>3. Buenavista Seaview Park</title>
		<image>images/seaview.jpg</image>
		<content>
			
		</content>
		<location>7W3R+7WW, Buenavista, Marinduque </location>
	</buenavista>
	<buenavista>
		<title>4. Malbog Sulphur Springs</title>
		<image>images/malbog.jpg</image>
		<content>Frequently visited by local and even foreign tourists located in Brgy. Malbog. It is a hot spring at the base of the inactive volcano Mt. Malindig, with therapeutic and natural healing waters.
		</content>
		<location>Located at the base of Mount Malindig in Buenavista, Marinduque </location>
	</buenavista>
	


	<!-- Torrijos -->
	<torrijos>
		<title>1. Poctoy White Beach</title>
		<image>images/poctoy.jpg</image>
		<content>Torrijos White Beach (Poctoy White Beach Resort), famous for its fine and powdery white sands, is one of the finest beaches in the Province of Marinduque. It is considered by the local and foreign tourists as one of which surpasses all other beach resorts in the island province in terms of location, accessibility, and geographical and physical features, added with the cool view of the clouds kissing the majestic Mt. Malindig and backgrounds of Bundok Peninsula and Romblon Island. Its approximately one kilometer stretch of white-sand beach offers visitors a unique beach experience. The white sand of the beach is suitable picnic ground, a great place to walk, and breathe some fresh air. Likewise, the water is sparkling blue, clean and clear, perfect for your getaway with the presence of coral reefs.
		</content>
		<location> Brgy. Poctoy, Torrijos Marinduque </location>
	</torrijos>

	<torrijos>
		<title>2. Freedom Park</title>
		<image>images/freedom.jpg</image>
		<content>Freedom Park (formerly Luneta Park) is located near the seashore, enticing the visitors with its soothing and relaxing ambiance and touch of the cool, fresh south winds. Because of its great potential of becoming a crowed drawer in terms of tourist spots, the area was developed and structured and now the largest park in the Province of Marinduque. It’s a splurging area that serves as an esplanade after a day’s work. On the left side, overlooking the park is a glimpse of the prominent Torrijos White Beach, while on the right side is the towering backdrop of Mt. Malindig. It gives liberty to look upon the majestic height of this highest mountain in Marinduque. The area is wide enough and definitely refreshing hangout anytime in a day. Palm trees serve as the roof of tables and benches and floor with bermuda grass. This park goes along with a clean seawall that offers different water activities.
		</content>
		<location>Rosas St., Torrijos, Marinduque  </location>
	</torrijos>
	<torrijos>
		<title>3. Pulang Lupa</title>
		<image>images/pulang lupa.jpg</image>
		<content>Pulang Lupa Historical Shrine Located in high in the mountains of Pulang Lupa, this historical park offers a sweeping panoramic view of the eastern seaboard of Marinduque. This shrine just outside of Torrijos town is home to the most famous battle in the Province of Marinduque during the Philippine-American War. This battle is one of the five inspirational battles where Filipinos defeated American occupying forces during this period in the Philippines. The mighty clash between Filipinos and American troops occurred last September 13, 1900 at “Kambindol” now known as Pulang Lupa, which was led by Colonel Maximo Abad. They surprised and defeated the Company of the United States 29th Volunteers led by Captain Deveraux Shields.
		</content>
		<location>  </location>
	</torrijos>
	<torrijos>
		<title>4. Ambango Beach and Rock Formation</title>
		<image>images/ambango.jpg</image>
		<content>Ambango Beach and Rock Formation is truly Torrijos’ hidden gems because even locals are hesitant to take the trip. It is one of the most underrated tourist spots in town. Even though it is a public beach, it rarely gets crowded. This unspoiled beach has a picturesque stretch of gray sand and crystal clear waters, making it the perfect place to go swimming and sunbathing. The journey requires physical strength and determination. Here, you can walk across the long stretches of the sand, traverse from one place to the other, marvel at the rock formations, take a dip in the tidal pool, jump off cliffs to the water, and lounge under the trees.
		</content>
		<location>Bonliw, Torrijos, Marinduque  </location>
	</torrijos>
	<torrijos>
		<title>5. Ka Amon Cave</title>
		<image>images/kaamon.jpg</image>
		<content>Ka Amon Cave (“Pilapil Cave”) was discovered on June 2, 1961 by Dr. Robert B. Fox, an anthropologist from the National Museum of the Philippines. It was named after Ka Amon Monterey of Barangay Bonliw who owns the lot. It is in the western part of the barangay and approximately 100 meters above sea level. And it is approximately 0.5 kilometer from the National Road and about five-minute walk from the Barangay Road. The cave was assessed by the University of the Philippines-Los Baños (UPLB) Team, the Provincial Cave Assessment Team (PCAT), the Provincial Environment and Natural Resources Office (PENRO)-Marinduque and the Sangguniang Barangay of Bonliw. Habitats found inside the cave were bats and insects in particular. The stalactites and stalagmites were visible and they serve as attractions to the tourists entering the cave.
		</content>
		<location>Bonliw, Torrijos Marinduque  </location>
	</torrijos>
	<torrijos>
		<title>6. Sibuyao Farms and Highlands</title>
		<image>images/sibuyao.jpg</image>
		<content>Due to the cool temperature in Barangay Sibuyao, farmers grow and organically produce fruits, and vegetables like lettuce, broccoli, cabbage, beans, cucumber, strawberry, some flowers used as repellant to insects, and herbals. They were trained and given technical assistance by the Provincial Agriculture Office (PAO) on reproducing plants that are suitable for cold weathers such as strawberry production. Now, a lot of tourists visit Sibuyao to witness how the strawberries grow and being taking care of. Along the National Highway near the boundaries of Barangays Sibuyao, Nangka and Maranlig is a tourist spot, which is almost 525 meters above sea level offering a 360-degree view of Marinduque’s eastern seaboard, Central Marinduque mountain range and a distant view of the Balagbag mountain range. During early morning and late afternoon treks along the rolling grasslands and pasture lands of the ridgeline, one can have “above the clouds experience” with a mild chilly temperature normal for these elevations – a favorite and popular stop for picture and video taking in the area.
		</content>
		<location>Sibuyao, Torrijos Marinduque  </location>
	</torrijos>
	<torrijos>
		<title>7. The Flinstone House</title>
		<image>images/flinstone.jpg</image>
		<content>This is the closest BedRock House of Fred and Wilma Flintstone,as you might have seen in movies before. A really unique Flintstone-house, who is built up with stone and cement only. All funitures ,beds,tables,lamps,is made of stone/cement ,marbol.The House is located in Torrijos,in the Island Marinduque, Philippines. Its located at the seaside,with a fantastic 180* seeview,and 180* mountain view. The price is for 1-12pax,but we can raise up to 20 pax with additional 20 USD/1000 pesos/pax/night.
		</content>
		<location>84P8+87C, Torrijos, Marinduque  </location>
	</torrijos>


	<!-- SANTA CRUZ -->
	<santacruz>
		<title>1. Maniwaya Island</title>
		<image>images/santa cruz.jpg</image>
		<content>Located in the town of Santa Cruz in Marinduque, Maniwaya Island is one of the most popular islands in the province. It is situated in the middle of Polo Island and Mompong Island. People often flock to Maniwaya to see and enjoy the white sand beaches. Its southwest and northeast sides both boast a kilometer stretch of shoreline. The southwest side is home to affordable accommodations and water activities like snorkeling and free diving. The northeast side of Maniwaya is where Palad Sandbar can be found. Because of its prime location, the island also offers stunning sunrise and sunset views.
		    When visiting Maniwaya Island, most locals recommend exploring the nearby must-see attractions like Palad Sandbar. The sandbar is a stretch of crushed coral sands in the middle of the sea, which only appears during low tide. Visitors usually snorkel to see the beautiful coral garden beneath the sand bar. 
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Maniwaya, Santa Cruz Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>2. Palad Sand Bar</title>
		<image>images/maniwaya.webp</image>
		<content> Palad Sandbar is one of a kind places for outdoor enthusiasts and beach lovers. 
		It features powdery white sands that flush through the crystal clear waters, which  appears during low tide.
		 It's advisable to go here in the morning when the tide is usually low. You can reach sandbar via a 30-minute boat ride  from Maniwaya

		</content>
		<location> Barangay Maniwaya, Santa Cruz Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>3. Ungab Rock Formation</title>
		<image>images/ungab.jpg</image>
		<content> If you want to see a beautiful rock formation you should visit Ungab Rock Formation Located in Mongpong Santa Cruz Marinduque.
		Upon arrival on the island, the Ungab Rock Formation is the first thing that will pique your interest. The huge colossal rock sits on the island’s turquoise waters and white sand. Carved out of the base rock is a triangular hole that forms a land bridge connecting you to the other side of the beach.  
		The giant boulder is a sight to behold and a perfect backdrop for your selfies and group photos. Plus, the water underneath the rock arch is shallow, making it a safe spot to swim for kids. The white sand is also a mixture of smooth pebbles and coral fragments.

		</content>
		<location> Mongpong, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>4. Bagumbungan Cave</title>
		<image>images/bagumbungan_cave.jpg</image>
		<content>Out of so many things to do in Marinduque, one adventure you should not let pass is a spelunking adventure at BAGUMBUNGAN CAVE in Sta Cruz.
		Bagumbungan Cave in Sitio Puti Brgy. San Isidro, Sta. Cruz Marinduque is for sure one of the best cave here in the Philippines. It is a 1.9 km. long cave and some part are still unexplored. It is protected by the Department of Environment and Natural Resources (DENR) with the help of San Isidro (Local Government Unit) to spare the cave from exploitation. According to our guide, it was discovered 7 years ago by the cave enthusiast and a tourism officer.
		 Since then the local government has been doing so much efforts in promoting this cave as their tourist destination in San Isidro. 
		</content>
		<location> Barangay San Isidro, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>5. Bathala Cave</title>
		<image>images/bathala-caves.jpg</image>
		<content>
			Experiencing Bathala Caves is one of the most must-try when you visit Marinduque Island. located at Sta. Cruz, Marinduque is a complex network of seven caves however only four of which have so far been explored.
			Bathala Cave is said to be mystical and repository of psychic power emanating from various points of universe. Bathala Caves is a complex network of caves that are said to be the playground of the Gods. Located in the rustic town of Sta. Cruz in Marinduque, the caves are believed to be mystical.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Ipil, Santa Cruz, Marinduque</location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>6. Kawa-Kawa Falls</title>
		<image>images/kawa-kawa.jpg</image>
		<content>Kawa -Kawa falls is located in Bangcuangan, Sta. Cruz, Marinduque. Kawa means "basin" because of a basin-like appearance. There are actually two basins, one from the top and the second at the lower part. Because there is a light rainfall before we went there, the water became a little dark but rest assured that is clean since there are caretakers in the area and the water is flowing continuously.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Bangcuangan, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>7. Altar Falls</title>
		<image>images/altar falls.jpg</image>
		<content> Altar falls is where you canswim freely and it was located at DevillA, Santa Cruz Marinduque. 
		Ito lugar na kung saan makakalimutan mo mga problema mo sa buhay
            ALTAR FALLS at devilla sta cruz marinduque
            sagot sa Summer nyo…
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Devilla, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>8. Bagakawa Falls</title>
		<image>images/bagakawafalls.jpg</image>
		<content>An Island Luxury Resort
			All 20 hectares of Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa are mountainous terrain, with its highest point at 114 meters above sea-level. To seasoned travelers, images of the picturesque island of Santorini in Greece will come into mind upon reaching the resort. Common to both are its rolling terrains and immaculate white buildings perched atop its cliffs: white structures that reflect the sun and contrast with the azure blue seas below.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Tambangan, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>9. LapResa o Tagpuan</title>
		<image>images/lapresa.jpg</image>
		<content>A Haven for Endangered Species in the Philippines. The sanctuary is home to a variety of flora and fauna, including rare and endangered species, making it a haven for nature lovers and conservationists. One of the highlights of the sanctuary is the Philippine tarsier, which is one of the smallest primates in the world and is considered a vulnerable species due to habitat loss and poaching. Aside from the tarsiers, the sanctuary also houses a variety of bird species, such as the Philippine eagle, the Palawan peacock-pheasant, and the Mindoro bleeding-heart dove. The area is also home to various plant species, including the Narra tree and the Rattan palm.
		Visiting the Marinduque Wildlife Sanctuary offers a unique opportunity to observe these animals and plants in their natural habitats while supporting their conservation efforts. The sanctuary is also an excellent place for outdoor activities such as birdwatching, trekking, and nature photography.
		</content>
		<location> It is boundery of Barangay Pulong Parang, Taytay, Haguimit and Masaguisi, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>10. Panuluyan</title>
		<image>images/panuluyan.jpg</image>
		<content>The very vision of Panuluyan Farmstay originates from the beautiful word “Panunuluyan” which symbolizes the Filipino culture of coming home, sleeping soundly in a kubo, and just hanging out at home with your loved ones over local home-cooked meals. This is exactly the concept of the place – they want the guests to experience peaceful rustic farm living. The farm features various crops and greens, but what most guests come back to are the chocolates produced using their harvest from the cacao farm. They serve chocolate-infused dishes and drinks!
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Masalukot, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>11. San Antonio Golf Course</title>
		<image>images/golfcourse.jpg</image>
		<content>An Island Luxury Resort
			All 20 hectares of Bellarocca Island Resort and Spa are mountainous terrain, with its highest point at 114 meters above sea-level. To seasoned travelers, images of the picturesque island of Santorini in Greece will come into mind upon reaching the resort. Common to both are its rolling terrains and immaculate white buildings perched atop its cliffs: white structures that reflect the sun and contrast with the azure blue seas below.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay San Antonio, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>12. DapDap Beach</title>
		<image>images/dapdap.jpg</image>
		<content>Dapdap Beach often serve as gathering places for friends and families, where they can bond, enjoy each other's company, and create lasting memories. Picnics, beach parties, and barbecues are common activities that bring people together in a convivial atmosphere.
		it;s popular mostly to the people who want to enjoy beaches that not so far in their location that located only in Santa Cruz.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Tagum, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>13. Sampitan Beach</title>
		<image>images/sampitan.jpg</image>
		<content>Sampitan Beach emanate a serene and peaceful ambiance, making them a sanctuary for relaxation and rejuvenation. The combination of gentle sea breezes, warm sand underfoot, and the vast expanse of the ocean fosters a sense of tranquility and calm.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Taytay, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>
	<santacruz>
		<title>14. Hakupan Island</title>
		<image>images/hakupan.jpg</image>
		<content>
			Hakupan island is located at Brgy,Botilao Sta.Cruz 
            Marinduque....a beautiful island with White sand, blue water and fascinating view!!!this island has cool atmosphere that makes it ideal for those wanting a relaxing retreat.This place surrounded by four islets near by the island. this island is a place ideal for,snorkeling,scubadiving, a camp site and observing marine life and also ideal for those who are nature lover.
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Botilao, Santa Cruz, Marinduque </location>
	</santacruz>


	<!-- mogpog -->

	
	<mogpog>
		<title>1. Paadjao Falls</title>
		<image>images/padjaofalls.jpg</image>
		<content>While Marinduque is famous for its scenic beaches, there is one enchanting waterfall that stands out from the rest of the Mogpog Marinduque tourist spots, the Paadjao Falls.
         Situated in Mogpog municipality, the Paadjao Falls is accessible via a 10-minute trek from the highway, which is only 5.5KM away.
		The hidden cascade gently flows from a 15-feet tall rocky cliff down to a 6-feet deep basin with cold and jade-green waters. It majestically nestles underneath the cool shade of verdant greenery and tall trees, making you feel a lot closer to nature. Surrounding the falls are huge and edgy rocks, so be extra careful when crossing the river and falls.
        Paadjao Falls is connected to the Mogpog River downstream. It is also an ideal picnic spot where guests can put up tents for camping. Aside from Paadjao Falls, there are other underrated waterfalls in Marinduque such as Norada Falls, Kawa Kawa Falls, and Bulusukan Falls.

        </content>
		<location> south west coast of the Marinduque province.  </location>
	</mogpog>
	<mogpog>
		<title>2. Balanacan View Deck</title>
		<image>images/balanacan.jpg</image>
		<content> Offers a 270 degree view of the northwestern portion of Mogpog, was constructed from a single storey galvanized iron roofing into a two-storey concrete slab view area.
		</content>
		<location> Balanacan, Mogpog, Marinduque </location>
	</mogpog>
	<mogpog>
		<title>3. Natangco White Beach</title>
		<image>images/natangco.jpg</image>
		<content> A protected marine sanctuary, natangco Island is part of barangay silangan, mogpog, marinduque. Sarrounded by 30 to 40 feet deep fringing reefs
		excellent for diving and snorkeling. the island can be reach by rented boats from barangay Ino and Barangay Balanacan. The Island boasts a strip 
		of white sand beach, pristine and clear waters and rocky island formations off its coast.
		</content>
		<location> Silangan, Mogpog, Marinduque. </location>
	</mogpog>
	<mogpog>
	<title>4. San Andres Island</title>
		<image>images/sanandres.jpg</image>
		<content> The Uninhabited island of San Andres in Silangan, mogpog is rich in marine life below. The island is swim-away from the white sand coast of the village. there are numerous rock shelters and forest areas on the 
		northern side of this island that is kept untapped and untouched by human shelters
		</content>
		<location> Silangan, Mogpog, Marinduque </location>
	</mogpog>


<!--                                        GASAN -->
	<gasan>
		<title>1. Gaspar Island </title>
		<image>images/gaspar.jpg</image>
		<content>The Tres Reyes Islands in Marinduque have soft sand and blue waters where you can spend a couple of hours taking photos, swimming, and beach bumming. One of the islands in the group is Gaspar Island; it is a popular destination because of its beautiful beachscape and relatively larger beach compared to the other two. This populated island is the perfect place to relax, unwind, and enjoy the rustic life of the province.
		Gaspar Island is a great place to go swimming, snorkeling, and beach bumming in. Lay on the sand for sunbathing and douse the heat in its clear cool waters. The islands are also picturesque, ideal for those who want to take pictures of beachscapes.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Pinggan Gasan, Marinduque. </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>2. Melchor Island </title>
		<image>images/melchor.jpg</image>
		<content>Marinduque’s Tres Reyes Islands have a beautiful beachscape and blue waters where you can spend a day taking pictures, swimming, and lazing on the beach. Melchor Island is part of the island hopping tour; it is the smallest of the three, but it still provides visitors with a nice idyllic place to relax and unwind. The rock formations add to its raw appeal and picturesque surroundings.
		Go swimming and beach bumming during your stay. There are rock formations dotting the island, which adds to its natural allure. The beautiful beachscape provides visitors with plenty of photo ops. From the island, you can get a glimpse of Malindig Volcano and mainland Marinduque, depending on the weather.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Pinggan Gasan, Marinduque. </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>3. Baltazar Island </title>
		<image>images/baltazar.webp</image>
		<content>Island hopping Marinduque’s Tres Reyes Islands is one of the things you can do while in the province; Baltazar Island is part of this tour. It provides you with a nice and beautiful place to go diving in and relax. The island is different from Melchor and Gaspar Islands. This place is a noteworthy destination for those who want a weekend getaway from the hustle and bustle of the metropolis.
		Baltazar Island isn’t as big as Gaspar Island, but it still has a good swimming area and beach. The island is a famous diving spot as it has a thriving underwater ecosystem worth exploring. However, the province has limited diving options and available equipment. If you have the skill and experience, you can dive to and explore the underwater cave in the area. Check out the old lighthouse while you’re there.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Pinggan Gasan, Marinduque. </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>4. Guingona Park </title>
		<image>images/guingona.jpg</image>
		<content>The largest park in Gasan, this is where the town's annual passion play is staged every Black Saturday, as well as the Gasang-Gasang Street Dancing Festival every Easter Sunday. The Gasan Public Library is located inside the park.
		</content>
		<location> San Jose Street, Barangay Uno, Gasan Marinduque </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>5. Reyes Park </title>
		<image>images/reyes.jpg</image>
		<content>Reyes Park in Barangay Dos serves as the Gasan boardwalk. Fairs are conducted in the park, and a wooden footbridge leading to nearby Barangay Dili can be seen (and crossed). The bridge is a landmark of Barangay Dili.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Dos, Gasan Marinduque</location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>6. Talao Cave </title>
		<image>images/.jpg</image>
		<content>Talao Cave in Barangay Tiguion is a series of twelve caves accessible from three mountain trails that can only be crossed on foot. The caves are located in the midst of a rain forest. A maze of caverns, sinkholes, and multi-level chambers located in the interior forested part of Brgy. Tiguion. Can be accessed by travelling the barangay road and trekking uphill to the cave’s location. The Provincial Cave Assessment Team have recommended this cave as Class II or can be used for ecotourism thru trained cave guides. This cave is included in the recently held 14th PSS National Caving Congress.
		</content>
		<location>Barangay Tiguion, Gasan Marinduque </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>7. Saint Joseph the Worker Parish </title>
		<image>images/parish.jpg</image>
		<content>Roman Catholic Road, Barangay Dos. Located on the second-highest point in Gasan, the church has a viewing platform with wonderful views of the town center below. A grand new church—believed to be the biggest in Marinduque—has replaced the old church (which was converted into an auditorium), with a large altarpiece at the end. While substantial work is complete, the church is not yet finished, and the church accepts donations for its eventual completion. 
		</content>
		<location> Barangay Dos, Gasan Marinduque</location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>8. Gasan Nature and Butterfly Park </title>
		<image>images/butterfly.webp</image>
		<content>Located on a rolling hill at the eastern edge of town, this nature park offers flower gardens, winding walkways, artificial waterfalls, picnic grove with butterfly cages maintained and managed municipal government adjacent to another municipal park.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Tiguion, Gasan Marinduque  </location>
	</gasan>
	<gasan>
		<title>9. Butterfly Farms </title>
		<image>images/bfarm.jpg</image>
		<content>Located near and on the town proper are butterfly farms that offers a glimpse of the butterfly life cycle though the live samples of butterfly larvae, pupae and full grown butterfly of several species inside big cages where live species freely flutter. Available are stuffed butterfly- based souvenir items.
		</content>
		<location>Brgy. Tiguion, Gasan Marinduque </location>
	</gasan>
</places>
